JONNA PANDER | DATA SCIENCE

Austin, TX · 512-964-2000

jpander@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/jonnapander · jonnapander.github.io · github.com/jonnapander

Environmental Consultant turned Information Solutions Consultant turned Data Science Professional with 3 years experience working with data and over a decade in the consulting industry helping clients solve problems.

SKILLS

- Python, R
- SQL
- Seaborn, Numpy, Scikit-Learn
- Data Analysis & Visualization
- Machine Learning

- Deep Learning
- Regressions
- Databases (SSMS, FileMaker)
- Gi
- Tableau

PROJECTS

Reddit Classification with NLP / API | NLP | Machine Learning

Scraped data from Reddit threads and built a binary classifier to identify which subreddit a given post originated from.

Extracting Flood Depths From Images / Python | Deep Learning

Utilized VGG16 architecture and keras to estimate depth of flood water from images of hurricane floods.

House Price Prediction / Python | Machine Learning

Used linear regression to estimate housing saleprice based on dataset with over 80 features.

EXPERIENCE

APRIL 2020 – JULY 2020, AUSTIN, TX DATA SCIENCE FELLOW, GENERAL ASSEMBLY

 Python, Data Cleaning/Exploration (Pandas, NumPy, SciPy), Machine Learning and Regression/Classification-based Modeling (Scikit-Learn, Statsmodels, Keras and TensorFlow), Webscraping/Data Mining (Requests, BeautifulSoup) and Visualization (Matplotlib, Seaborn)

JULY 2015 – FEBRUARY 2020, AUSTIN, TX

ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT, BSI EHS SERVICES AND SOLUTIONS

- Automated processing of chemical inventory data using SQL, SQL Server Management Studio, and FileMakerPro for expedited reporting of inventories for dozens of clients
- Led workshops with cross-functional teams for objectives such as rolling out a custom software configuration for streamlining the completion of daily construction safety checklists
- Created analytics reports and dashboards for insights into audits and inspections findings
- Interfaced with regulatory agencies to assist clients in compliance and permitting

FEBRUARY 2011 – NOVEMBER 2014, AUSTIN, TX

ENVIRONMENTAL CONSULTANT, SPIRIT ENVIRONMENTAL, LLC

 Determined calculation methodologies and prepared emissions calculations in Excel, process flow diagram drawings, site maps, regulatory reviews, and application forms for permitting sources of air emissions

EDUCATION

JULY 2020, AUSTIN, TX

DATA SCIENCE IMMERSIVE, GENERAL ASSEMBLY

Three-month program focused on real-world applications of data science principles and best practices including, data acquisition, data cleaning and wrangling, predictive modeling, and visualization strategies.

DECEMBER 2006, COLLEGE STATION, TX

BS RANGELAND ECOLOGY & MANAGEMENT, TEXAS A&M UNIVERSITY

This degree program is now called Ecosystem Science & Management. Coursework was heavy in plant identification and environmental assessments.